A Guide to the E. Griffith Dodson Papers, 1923-1962
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
E. Griffith Dodson Papers, 1923-1962
Library of Virginia
25244
13.15 cu. ft., in part photocopies
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession 25244, Gift of E. Griffith Dodson, Richmond, Virginia, 27 October 1960; Accession 39503, Purchased from Jan Hanna, Belfast, Maine.
Biographical/Historical Information
Edward Griffith Dodson was born in Norfolk, Virginia on 30 April 1884. He received a law degree from the University of Virginia in 1907. He married Harriotte Jones Winchester of Macon, Georgia on 29 January 1913. Dodson served on the Norfolk Board of Alderman from 1912 to 1918; member of the Democratic State Central Committee from 1916 to 1938; member of the Virginia House of Delegates from 1918 to 1920; Virginia State Senate, 1922; member of the State Commission on Conservation and Development from 1926 to 1934; and Clerk of the Virginia House of Delegates from 1934 to 1962. He was also director of the Seaboard Citizens National Bank of Norfolk. Dodson also authored several books on Virginia history, including The Capitol of the Commonwealth of Virginia at Richmond (1937), The General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Virginia, 1919-1939 (1939), and Speakers and Clerks of the Virginia House of Delegates, 1776-1955 (1956). He died in Norfolk, Virginia on 8 April 1969.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 1923-1962, of E. Griffith Dodson, including correspondence, as well as files relating to his work on several books on Virginia history. The CORRESPONDENCE FILES contain incoming and copies of outgoing correspondence. Correspondents include Arthur Bevan, R. E. Burson, Harry F. Byrd, A. C. Carson, William E. Carson, Colgate W. Darden, Hamilton J. Eckenrode, Elmer O. Fippin, Junius Fishburn, Richard A. Gilliam, Chapin Jones, Lee Long, Thomas W. Ozlin, George C. Peery, John Garland Pollard, Rufus G. Roberts, and Coleman Wortham. There is a substantial amount of correspondence between Dodson and Harry F. Byrd. When Byrd ran for Governor of Virginia in 1925 against G. Walter Mapp of Accomack County, Dodson served as his campaign director in Norfolk. The correspondence in this portion of the collection documents Byrd's stance on campaign issues such as liquor law enforcement, voter registration procedures, revisions of the fee system, tax equalization, road building and the gas tax, and Byrd's votes on the 1916 Vice Bill and Bible Bill while serving in the Virginia General Assembly, as well as machine politics, and economy, efficiency, and simplicity in state government. The correspondence between Byrd and Dodson continued while Byrd was Governor, and later United States Senator. Most of the correspondence from this time period focuses on state and national issues, and political appointments.
The remainder of correspondence files detail Dodson's work as a member of the State Commission on Conservation and Development. There is a large amount of correspondence with William E. Carson, who served as chairman, as well as other members of the Commission. Topics covered include the use of Virginia's scenic and historic assets to attract tourists and industry, and plans to foster recreational areas, such as the creation of the Shenandoah National Park. There is a large amount of documentation concerning the park's pledge campaign, and efforts to reduce the park's size. Other issues covered include the preparation of a system of historical markers placed along the state's highways, the formation of a state park system, and the move to reorganize the Commission under Governor Pollard. There is also a box of miscellaneous publications, annual reports, legislation, programs, newsletters, pamphlets, and brochures concerning agriculture, conservation and development, geology, parks and water power in Virginia and other states.
THE CAPITOL OF THE COMMONWEALTH OF VIRGINIA AT RICHMOND series contains files on various individuals and topics included in this volume which was first published in 1937. This series is alphabetical, and includes correspondence seeking information on portraits, busts, and statues of all the governors of Virginia since 1776, and other famous Virginians, contained in the Capitol, and biographical information on those particular individuals. Also contained in this series are miscellaneous notes and a bound volume of cut-up galleys. Accession 39503 is a copy of the book inscribed by Gov. George Campbell Peery to Dodson's wife, which also includes a handwritten dedication by Dodson, as well as various annotations throughout. This volume is number seven of two thousand printed.
THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY OF THE COMMONWEALTH OF VIRGINIA, 1919-1939, series contains biographical questionnaires and sketches, as well as correspondence, which Dodson used to compile this register of members published in 1939. The biographical questionnaires were sent out to all members or their descendants, were completed, and returned. These questionnaires were then used to compile member sketches which are included in the book.
The SPEAKERS AND CLERKS OF THE VIRGINIA HOUSE OF DELEGATES, 1776-1955, series includes correspondence and research notes concerning individuals who served as Speaker or Clerk of the Virginia House of Delegates. The correspondence is with the particular individual or his descendants, and includes genealogical and biographical information which Dodson used to compile his sketches for the book which was published in 1956. There is a large amount of information on John James Beckley, Benjamin Harrison, Charles Hay, John Winston Jones, Larkin Smith, John Stewart, and Zephaniah Turner, Jr. Also included in this series are court orders, resolutions of respect, and memorials of former members, miscellaneous research notes, as well as various drafts, some of them bound, a card index, and wood block printing plates used in the production of the volume.
Also included in this collection is a bound typescript entitled "The General Assembly of Virginia, 1885-1918, Index" which Dodson compiled in 1959, and had apparently hoped to publish. The volume is an alphabetical index of entries mostly in House journals and partly in Senate journals, including resolutions, documents, reports, addresses, election of judges, State officers, House officers, electoral boards, other confirmations of boards and school superintendents, and items of historical interest. This volume was intended to be a supplement to his book THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY OF THE COMMONWEALTH OF VIRGINIA, 1919-1939. The volume also includes a listing of all counties and cities in Virginia showing their several judicial circuits from time to time.
Arrangement
Arranged in four series: I. Correspondence Files. II. The Capitol of the Commonwealth of Virginia at Richmond. III. The General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Virginia, 1919-1939. IV. Speakers and Clerks of the Virginia House of Delegates, 1776-1955.
Contents List
- Correspondence Files
  - Burson, R. E. (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Byrd, Harry F.
    - Campaign Correspondence
      - 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 1925 (November-December) (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - 1925 (October) (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - 1925 (September) (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - 1925 (August 12-31) (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - 1925 (August 1-11) (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - 1925 (July 16-31) (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - 1925 (July 1-15) (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - 1925 (June) (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - 1925 (May) (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - 1924 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Campaign Literature (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Lists of Contributors (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - General Correspondence
      - 25 April 1934 - 2 March 1935 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - 3 March 1933 - 25 April 1934 (Box 2, Folder 2-4)
      - 14 September 1930 - 2 March 1933 (Box 2, Folder 5-7)
      - 4 January 1928 - 13 September 1930 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
      - Luncheon - Norfolk - 26 April 1928 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - 7 May 1926 - 3 January 1928 (Box 2, Folder 5-7)
      - 2 November 1923 - 6 May 1926 (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
  - "C" (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Carson, Judge A. C. (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
  - Carson, William E.
    - 5 October 1934 - 31 December 1934 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - 1 September 1933 - 5 October 1934 (Box 4, Folder 5-8)
    - 1 January 1932 - 31 August 1933 (Box 4, Folder 9-12)
    - 14 May 1930 - 31 December 1931 (Box 4, Folder 13-14)
    - 14 May 1930 - 31 December 1931 (continued) (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
    - 1 January 1929 - 6 May 1930 (Box 5, Folder 3-5)
    - 11 May 1926 - 31 December 1928 (Box 5, Folder 6-8)
    - Speeches, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Chamber of Commerce (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Civilian Defense (Box 5, Folder 11-13)
  - Collector of Customs (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Constitutional Amendments (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Committee of One Hundred (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - "D" (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Dale Point (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Darden, Colgate W., 3 August 1933 - 20 December 1934 (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
  - Democratic Committee, Second Congressional District and Parke P. Deans, 19 January 1932 - 14 November 1934 (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
  - "E" (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Eckenrode, H. J., 9 September 1927 - 1 November 1934 (Box 6, Folder 8-12)
  - Epes, Louis S. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - "F" (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Farrar, Thomas L., 30 December 1927 - 22 December 1934 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Fippin, Elmer O.
    - 15 November 1929 - 2 July 1930 (Box 6, Folder 16-17)
    - 30 March 1928 - 14 November 1929 (Box 7, Folder 1-4)
    - 6 August 1926 - 30 March 1928 (Box 7, Folder 5-8)
  - Fishburn, Junius P. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - "G" (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Garden Club (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Gilliam, Richard A.
    - 15 May 1933 - 17 December 1934 (Box 7, Folder 12-14)
    - 15 July 1930 - 27 April 1933 (Box 8, Folder 1-4)
  - "H" (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Highway Markers (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Historic Sites (Box 8, Folder 7-9)
  - "J" (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Jones, Chapin (Box 8, Folder 11-12)
  - "L" (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Legislature - 1932 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Long, Lee (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - "M" (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - "Mc" (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Marker Legends (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Monthly Statistical Reports, Division of History and Archaeology, 1929-1934 (Box 9, Folder 6-11)
  - Mosquito District - Virginia Beach (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - "N" (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - "O" (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Ozlin, Thomas W. (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - "P" (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Peery, George C. (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Pollard, John Garland (Box 9, Folder 18-19)
  - Porter - Designer of the Virginia (Merrimac) (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - "R" (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Report of the Findings of Mr. R. E. Burson on the George Washington Grist Mill, Situated on Dogue Creek Run, Mount Vernon, Virginia - March, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Report of the Nature and Status of the Work of the Virginia Forest Service - 4 August 1926 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Report of the Virginia Geological Survey (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Roberts, Rufus G. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - "S" (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
  - Shenandoah National Park Division - S. H. Marsh, Supervisor (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Shenandoah National Park Fund
    - List of Unpaid Pledges - Cities (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - List of Unpaid Pledges - Counties (Accomack - Franklin) (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - List of Unpaid Pledges - Counties (Frederick - Richmond) (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - List of Unpaid Pledges - Counties (Roanoke - Wythe) (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Past Due Notes, Outstanding and Demand Notes, Special Pledges Not Included on Lists, Money Pledges to be Transferred to Land, 1932-1933 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - List of Pledges, Norfolk, as of 20 June 1927 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - State Commission on Conservation and Development
    - Staff Conference Minutes, 12 June 1932 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Quarterly Staff Meeting, 13 July 1934 - Minutes and Division Reports (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Meeting Program, 10 August 1934 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - State Geological Survey - Laws Creating State Foresters' Office (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - State Geologist (Box 11, Folder 1-3)
  - Stewart, John
    - Copies of Court Records (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Signatures (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 6-8)
  - "T" (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Telgrams Sent, 1924-1930 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Adam Thorowgood House (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Tidewater Park (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Travel Expense Vouchers (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - "U" (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - "V" (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Virginia Forest Service (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Seashore State Park Association (Box 12, Folder 3-5)
  - Virginia State Parks
    - Progress Report, 31 March 1934 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Progress Report, 1 July 1934 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Project Report, 31 March 1934 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - "W" (Box 12, Folder 9-10)
  - Water Power and Development Commission - Report, 1926 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Wortham, Coleman (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Zuger, A. P. (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Publications, Annual Reports, Legislation, Programs, Newsletters, Pamphlets, and Brochures re: Agriculture, Conservation and Development, Geology, Parks, and Water Power in Virginia and Other States (Box 13)
- The Capitol of the Commonwealth of Virginia at Richmond
  - Bacon, Nathaniel (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Barbour, James (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Berkeley, Norborne (Lord Botetourt) (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Bigger, John Bell (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Braxton, Carter (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Brooke, Robert (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Cameron, William E. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Campbell, David (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Clark, George Rogers (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Culpeper, Lord Thomas (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Daniel, John Warwick (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Davis, Jefferson (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Davis, Westmoreland (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - De La Warr, Lord (Thomas West) (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Echols, Edward (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Effingham, Francis (Lord Howard of) (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Ellyson, J. Taylor (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Flag of Virginia (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Floyd, John (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Giles, William B. (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Hale, Peyton G. (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Harrison, William Henry (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Henry, Patrick (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Holliday, Frederick W. M. (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Houston, Sam (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Jackson, Thomas Jonathan (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Jefferson, Thomas (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Johnson, Joseph (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Johnston, Joseph E. (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Kemper, James L. (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - LaFayette, Marquis de (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Lee, Fitzhugh (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Lee, Francis Lightfoot (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Lee, Richard Henry (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Lee, Robert E. (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Letcher, John (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - Lewis, Andrew (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - Lewis, Meriwether (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Lomax, John Tayloe (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Lybrook, A. M. (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - McCormick, Cyrus H. (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - McDowell, James (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - McGuire, Hunter Holmes (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - McKinney, Philip W. (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - Madison, James (Box 14, Folder 45)
  - Mann, William Hodges (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - Marshall, John (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - Martin, Thomas S. (Box 14, Folder 48)
  - Mason, George (Box 14, Folder 49)
  - Massey, John E. (Box 14, Folder 50)
  - Maurey, Matthew Fontaine (Box 14, Folder 51)
  - Monroe, James (Box 14, Folder 52)
  - Montague, Andrew J. (Box 14, Folder 53)
  - Nelson, William (Box 14, Folder 54)
  - Newberry, Samuel H. (Box 14, Folder 55)
  - Nicholas, Wilson Cary (Box 14, Folder 56)
  - Peery, George C. (Box 14, Folder 57)
  - Pollard, John Garland (Box 14, Folder 58)
  - Preston, James P. (Box 14, Folder 59)
  - Randolph, Beverley (Box 14, Folder 60)
  - Randolph, Peyton (Box 14, Folder 61)
  - Randolph, Thomas Mann (Box 14, Folder 62)
  - Robertson, Wyndham (Box 14, Folder 63)
  - Seal of the Commonwealth (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Smith, George William (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Smith, Captain John (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Spotswood, Alexander (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - State Flower (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Stephens, Alexander H. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Stuart, Henry C. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Swanson, Claude A. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Taylor, Zachary (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Tazewell, Littleton Waller (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Trinkle, E. Lee (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Tyler, J. Hoge (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Valentine, Lila Meade (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Washington, George (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Wells, Henry H. (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Willard, Joseph E. (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Williams, B. F. (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Wilson, Woodrow (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Wood, James R. (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Wythe, George (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Index to The Capitol of the Commonwealth of Virginia (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 15, Folder 22-25)
  - Miscellaneous Notes for Second Edition (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Bound Volume of Cut-Up Galleys (Box 15, Folder n/a)
- The General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Virginia, 1919-1939
  - Biographical Questionnaires and Sketches
    - Blank (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - A (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - B (Box 16, Folder 3-6)
    - C (Box 16, Folder 7-9)
    - D (Box 16, Folder 10-11)
    - E (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - F (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - G (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
    - H (Box 17, Folder 3-5)
    - I-J (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - K (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - L (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Mc (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - M (Box 17, Folder 10-11)
    - N (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - O (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - P (Box 17, Folder 14-15)
    - Q (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - R (Box 18, Folder 2-3)
    - S (Box 18, Folder 4-7)
    - T (Box 18, Folder 8-9)
    - U-V (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - W (Box 18, Folder 11-14)
    - X-Y-Z (Box 18, Folder 15)
- Speakers and Clerks of the Virginia House of Delegates, 1776-1955
  - Allen, Henry C. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Barbour, James (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Baldwin, John B. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Banks, Linn (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Beckley, John James (Box 19, Folder 5-6)
  - Bigger, John Bell and Thomas H. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Brewer, Richard L., Jr. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Brown, J. Sinclair (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Byrd, Richard E. (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Cardwell, William D. (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Cox, Edwin P. (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Crutchfield, Oscar M. (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Dodson, E. Griffith and Dovell, Ashton (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Fowler, Isaac C. (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Gilmer, Thomas W. (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Goode, William O. (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Gordon, William F., Jr. (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Hanger, Marshall (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Harrison, Benjamin (Box 19, Folder 20-21)
  - Harrison, Edmund (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Hay, Charles (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
  - Holleman, Joel (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Holmes, Hugh (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Hopkins, George W. and Henry L. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Houston, Harry R. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Johnston, Peter, Jr. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Jones, John Winston (Box 20, Folder 8-11)
  - Kemper, James L. (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Lacy, Benjamin Watkins (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Lee, Richard Henry (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Mann, William Henry (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Massenburg, G. Alvin (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Mathews, Thomas (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - McCaull, Patrick H. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Moore, E. Blackburn (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Munford, George W. and William (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Nelson, Hugh and Ozlin, Thomas W. (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Pendleton, Edmund (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Pleasants, James, Jr. (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Prentis, Joseph (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Randolph, Edmund (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Ryan, John F. (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Saunders, E. W. (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Sheffey, Hugh W. and Baldwin, John B. (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Smith, Larkin (Box 21, Folder 15-19)
  - Southall, Valentine Wood (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Stanard, Robert (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Stanley, Thomas B. (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Stevenson, Andrew (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Stewart, John
    - Notes (Box 22, Folder 1-5)
    - Subjects
      - B (Box 22, Folder 6-7)
      - C (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - D (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - G (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - H-I-J (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - L (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - M (Box 22, Folder 13)
      - N (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - P (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - R (Box 22, Folder 16)
      - S (Box 22, Folder 17)
      - T-U-V (Box 22, Folder 18)
      - W (Box 22, Folder 19)
      - X-Y-Z (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Strother, James French (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Tazewell, John (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Tucker, Henry St. George, Jr. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Turner, Zephaniah, Jr. (Box 23, Folder 4-5)
  - Tyler, John, Sr. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Williams, John W./Wirt, William/Wise, John/Wythe, George (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Court Orders, Resolutions of Respect, Memorials (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
  - Miscellaneous Research Notes (Box 24, Folder 3-8)
  - Final Copy - Duplicate Pages (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Drafts (Box 24, Folder 10-11)
  - Draft - 1st Revision (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Draft - Copy Corrected to 12/26/53 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Draft - Same as Original Dated 9/3/54 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Paperback Edition (Box 25, Folder n/a)
  - Three Bound Drafts (Box 25, Folder n/a)
  - The General Assembly of Virginia, 1885-1918 - Index and State Officers, Judges, Boards, 1885-1938 (bound typescript) (Box 25, Folder n/a)
  - Card Index (Box 26, Folder n/a)
  - Wood Block Printing Plates (Box 27-28)